Guide to the McGraw-Hill Marketing Information Center Vertical File, 1948-1991
The John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
- Alphabetical, Topical, Keyword Index
  Single Ad Effects: ADV 50:2-2.1
  Single Advertiser Publications: ADV 35:4-6.2.7
  Single Copy Sales: ADV 50:5-4.10.1
  Site Selection Handbooks: ADM 0:2-10.7.5
  Situational Theory: ADM 0:2-7.21
  Size of Issue: ADV 50:5-5.11
  Size of Sales Force, optimizing: SAL 10:4-3
  Size of Space: ADV 50:8 (*)
  Skills Inventories: ADM 0:2-8.21.12
  Slogans, corporate: ADM 0:2-10.21
  Small Business
  Its Role and Problems: ADM 0:2-4.16.1
  Reports of the Select Committee on Small Business of the U.S. Senate: ADM 0:2-4.16.3
  SBA Publications: ADM 0:2-4.16.4.1
  Starting and Managing: ADM 0:2-4.16.2
  The Small Business Administration: What it is; What it does: ADM 0:2-4.16.4
  Small Orders: MKT 10:4
  Social and Ethical Responsibilities, corporate: ADM 0:2-10.32
  Social/Ethical Concept in marketing: MKT 5:2-10
  Sociobiology: MKT 50:2-1.42
  Socio/Economic Influence of Advertising: ADV 0:2
  Sources of Information of Consumer Purchasers: MKT 65:7-1
  Sources of Information (Marketing); see writeup at beginning of Marketing Series: MKT 50:7 (*)
  Sources of Information of Purchasing Influences: MKT 65:5
  Sources of Overseas Marketing Information: IOP 10:3-2.1.1
  Span of Control: ADM 0:1-5
  Speaking: ADM 0:2-7.2.10
  Speaking, salespersons: SAL 5:6-8
  Special Interest Copy: ADV 50:4-3.28
  Special Issues, as an advertising medium: ADV 50:5-5.12
  Special Issues Planned by McGraw-Hill Publications: ADV 50:5-5.12.1
  Special Sections, copy: ADV 50:4-3.12.1
  Specialty Advertising Media (calendars, combs, business gifts, etc.): ADV 35:4-14
  Specialty Magazines: ADV 35:4-6.2
  Spectral/Cross-Spectral Analysis: MKT 50:2-1.43
  Spouses: ADM 0:2-7.22
  Spouses, sales: SAL 5:6-9
  Spread vs. Bunched (publication format for advertising): ADV 50:7-7
  Spreads and Inserts: ADV 50:8-3
  Staff-Line/Staff-Staff Relationships: ADM 0:1-5
  Standardization (in international advertising): IOP 10:2-4.3
  Standardized Marketing: IOP 10:1-4
  Standards/Disclosure Forms for Media Research: ADV 50:5-5.10.6
  Starch-INRA Hooper/IAA World Advertising Expenditures: IOP 10:2-10.1
  Starting a New Agency: ADV 5:13
  Starting a New Magazine: ADV 35:4-6.3
  Statistics, use of: ADM 0:2-7.2.11
  Steps to a Sale: History: ADV 35:1-4
  Strategic Planning: ADM 0:2-9 (*)
  Stress: ADM 0:2-8.7
  Subliminal Advertising: ADV 50:9-14
  Subscription Sales, circulation: ADV 50:5-4.14.1
  Suggestion Systems: ADM 0:2-8.18
  Summer Advertising: ADV 50:2-5.1
  Summertime Selling: SAL 40:16
  Supervisor's Job: ADM 0:2-7.23
  Surplus Property Buying/Marketing: MKT 70:3
  Survey(s) of Buying Power, S&MM: MKT 50:2-4.1.2
  Survey(s) of Industrial and Commercial Buying Power, S&MM: MKT 50:2-4.1.3
  Sworn Statements: ADV 50:5-4.3.5
  Syndicated Audience Research (Simmons, TGI Commentary/Controversy/Merger): ADV 50:5-4.2.2
  Syracuse Study: ADV 50:5-4.2.1
  Systems Concept: MKT 5:2-11
  Systems Selling: MKT 5:2-11 (*)
  Systems Theory in Management: ADM 0:2-7.24
  T
  T & E Expenses: SAL 20:4-4
  T-Group Training: ADM 0:2-8.21.11
  TV, as an advertising medium: ADV 35:4-2.2
  TV Rating System: ADV 35:4-2.2.1
  Tachistoscope Testing: ADV 50:9-15
  Tariffs and Trade Policies: Imports: IOP 0:4
  Taste in Advertising: ADV 25 (*)
  Taxing of Advertising Services: ADV 25:6
  Taylor Instrument Study (of the business paper reading environment): ADV 40:3-7.1
  Teaching Machines: ADM 0:2-8.21.9.1
  Technical Staff, agency: ADV 5:10-10
  Technical Writing: ADM 0:2-7.2.13.1
  Technological Forecasting: MKT 50:2-1.44
  Technology Assessment/Transfer: ADM 0:2-4.15.6
  Technology Transfer, international: IOP 5:2-2.6
  Telemarketing: SAL 40:17
  Telephone Interviewing/Surveys: MKT 50:2-2.4
  Tele-Text/Terminal and Videoconferences: ADM 0:2-7.2.5.3
  Tell All, copy: ADV 50:4-2.1
  Temporary Workers: ADM 0:2-8.19
  Termination: ADM 0:2-8.21.13.3
  Terms and Definitions, economic: ADM 0:2-4.5.1
  Terms and Definitions, marketing: MKT 0:6
  Terms and Definitions, marketing research: MKT 50:1-2
  Terms and Definitions, media/advertising: ADV 35:6
  Territories, sales: SAL 10:5-5
  Terrorism, international: IOP 10:3-3
  Testimonial Copy: ADV 50:4-3.29
  Test Marketing: MKT 60:2-6
  Testing and Research, direct mail: ADV 35:3-13
  Testing: aptitude/psychological, sales: SAL 35:1-1
  Testing, personnel: ADM 0:2-8.20
  Testing, product: MKT 35:5
  The New York Times, annual international economic review (discontinued): IOP 0:6-2
  Theories X, Y and Z: ADM 0:2-7.26
  Thick vs. Thin Publications: ADV 50:5-5.11
  Tide: reader action series: ADV 40:2-3.1
  Time and Territory Management and Control, salespersons: SAL 5:6-5
  Time Conservation: ADM 0:2-7.4.3
  Time Series Analysis: MKT 50:2-1.45
  Time Spent Reading: ADV 40:3-7.6
  Tomorrow's Management: ADM 0:2-7.27
  Top Management's Involvement in the Industrial Communications Process: ADV 0:4-1
  Top Management's Role in Marketing: MKT 40:1-1
  Top Markets, Advertising Age (discontinued): MKT 50:2-4.1.4
  Townsend Points: ADV 50:4-3.30
  Trade Associations: MKT 80
  Trade Associations, overseas: IOP 10:5
  Trade Characters: ADM 0:2-10.21
  Trade Fairs: IOP 10:2-11.1
  Trade Missions: IOP 10:2-11.2
  Trade Names: ADM 0:2-10.21
  Trade Relations/Reciprocity: MKT 65:4
  Trade Show Trends, audience statistics: MKT 25:3
  Trade Zones: IOP 0:5
  Trademarks: ADM 0:2-10.21
  Trademarks in Copy: ADV 50:4-3.31
  Trading Markets, by country and/or region: IOP 10:4 (*)
  Training and Development: ADM 0:2-8.21 (*)
  Agency: ADV 5:10-7
  International: ADM 0:2-8.21.7
  Personnel: ADM 0:2-8.21 (*)
  Sales: SAL 35:2
  Sales Management: SAL 10:3
  Transference (in international advertising): IOP 10:2-4.3
  Transit Advertising: ADV 35:4-15
  Truth in Advertising: ADV 25 (*)
  Turnover, circulation: ADV 50:5-4.15
  Turnover, sales staff: SAL 15:5-6
  Turnover (why people leave jobs): ADM 0:2-8.21.13
  U
  U.S. Government as an Advertiser: MKT 70:2-1.2
  U.S. Government Purchasing, Specifications and Sales Directories: MKT 70:1-1
  Umbrella Advertisements: ADV 50:9-1
  Unionization, white collar: ADM 0:2-8.22
  Unit Counts: ADV 50:5-4.16
  Universe/Total Audience Measurement and Research Concepts/Management and Principles: ADV 50:5-4.2
  Unusual Overseas Payments: IOP 5:3-5
  V
  Validity/Verification/Reliability Procedures and Controls: MKT 50:2-1.47
  VALS: MKT 50:2-1.32
  Value Added Taxation (VAT): MKT 35:7
  Value Analysis: MKT 65:6
  Van Diver Studies (on the impact of industrial advertising on sales): ADV 40:2-4.3
  Variance/Covariance Analysis: MKT 50:2-1.46
  Angelo R. Venezian, ad volume forecasts and historical statistics: ADV 55:1-2.2
  Venture Team Approach, to new product development: MKT 60:1-2
  Verification/Validity/Reliability Procedures and Controls: MKT 50:2-1.47
  Verified Audit Circulation (VAC): ADV 50:5-4.3.4
  Vertical Integration: MKT 5:2-12
  Video-Based Training: ADM 0:2-8.21.9.1
  Videoconferences: ADM 0:2-7.2.5.3
  Videotex(t) Publishing: ADV 35:1-6.3
  Visual and Instructional Aids: ADM 0:2-7.2.12
  Visual Presentation of Advertising (the characteristics of well-read ads): ADV 50:9 (*)
  Vocabulary Building, salespersons: SAL 5:6-8
  Voice Pitch Analysis (VOPAN): MKT 50:2-1.48
  W
  Warranties, product: MKT 35:5
  Wartime Economy, advertising in: ADV 0:3-3
  Wave Scheduling, in advertising: ADV 50:2-3
  Wearout: ADV 50:2-4 (*)
  L.D.H. Weld, ad volume statistics: ADV 55:3-1
  Wholesaling: MKT 0:5
  Winter Advertising: ADV 50:2-5.2
  Women
  in Communications: MKT 40:3-2.2
  in Copy: ADV 50:4-3.32
  in Management: ADM 0:2-7.28
  in Marketing: MKT 40:3-1.2
  in Selling: SAL 5:4
  Marketing to: MKT 50:2-4.2.1.3
  Women's Magazines: ADV 35:4-6.2.5
  Word-of-Mouth Advertising: ADV 35:4-16
  World Advertising Expenditures, Starch-INRA Hooper/IAA: IOP 10:2-10.1
  World Business/Economic Forecasts and Reviews: IOP 0:6 (*)
  Writing: ADM 0:2-7.2.13
  Writing, research report: MKT 50:4
  Writing, salespersons: SAL 5:6-7
  Writing, technical: ADM 0:2-7.2.13.1
  Y
  Charles Yang, ad volume statistics: ADV 55:3-1.1
  Yellow Pages: ADV 35:4-17
  Youth Magazines: ADV 35:4-6.2.6
  Youths, marketing to: MKT 50:2-4.2.1.4
  Z
  Zero-Base Budgeting: ADM 0:2-6.1.4
  Zero Defects: ADM 0:2-4.12
  Zip Analysis and Research: MKT 50:2-4.5